Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
真っ白な景色にいま誘われて
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
僕は行くよ　まだ見ぬ世界へ
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
迷子のまま旅していた
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
鼠色の空の下
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
日替わりの地図 いくつもの夢が滲んでいた
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
いつかはさ
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
ちっぽけな僕のこの歩幅でも
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
あの雲の向こうまで行けるかな
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
強がって
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
キズついた
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
心透かしたように
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
降り出した
Furidashita
And the raindrops
雨粒たちが
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
乱反射繰り返す
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
真っ直ぐな光が
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
交差して
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
行き先も告げぬまま
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
どこまでも
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
突き抜ける
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
淡い残像　両目に焼きつけて
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
この空の下
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
どんなとこにいても
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
届くはずなんだ
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
まだ見ぬ世界へ
Mada minu sekai e
This is the bullet used in the murder of Brigadier General Hughes.
ヒューズ准将殺害に使用された銃弾だ
.45 caliber, and only one shot was fired.
口径は４５　使用弾数１発
I'd like to say the murderer was skilled, but it was a close proximity shot.
腕がいいと言いたいが
至近距離からだ
Not impossible for a woman to do.
女性でも十分可能だよ
What is the caliber of your gun?
君の使用している銃の口径は？
.45.
４５口径です
This is your ammunition request application.
これは　君の銃弾補充申請だ
Am I right?
間違いないね？
It's written here you only needed to be supplied with one shot.
ここには１発と書いてある
What did you use it for?
何に使ったんだね？
As it says right there,
そこにも書いてありますが
I used it at Research Laboratory 5, while I escorted Edward Elric...
エドワード·エルリック護衛の際　第五研究所で…
But Research Laboratory 5 is closed down, and there shouldn't be anyone there.
第五研究所は閉鎖され　無人のはずだ
But there were.
...According to you.
と　君は主張する
Should I order a search for this bullet you supposedly shot?
使用したという弾を　探させようか？
Research Laboratory 5 is in ruins now due to an unknown explosion.
第五研究所は　謎の爆発で　がれきの山です
So the place where you say you used
your gun is usually unvisited by people,
君が銃を使用したと主張する場所は　本来無人であり
and even if we wanted to search for
the bullet, it'd be under a heap of rubble...
弾を探し出そうにも　がれきの下というわけか
There's witness testimony stating you left the scene of the crime, on the exact date and time it occurred.
当日　犯行時刻に
現場から立ち去る　君の姿を目撃したという証言がある
That's ridiculous!
そんなバカな！
Compose yourself.
落ち着きたまえ
What were you doing at the time?
その時間　何をしていたんだね？
I was on leave that day and at my parents' house.
あの日は　休みで　両親の家にいました
You can confirm with them.
両親に確認してみてください
Testimony from family members or people whom you are close with cannot be accepted as an alibi.
家族　および　親しい間柄の証言は
アリバイとして認められない
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross is currently being interrogated.
マリア·ロス少尉は　ただいま尋問中です
Though you may be her superior, I cannot allow you to see her.
上官であっても　面会は無理です
I see...
そうか…
Major Armstrong!
アームストロング少佐
Sergeant Brosh.
ブロッシュ軍曹
You were here, too, Major?
少佐も来ていらしたのですか？
Yeah. Are you here for Second Lieutenant Ross?
うむ　ロス少尉のことか？
Yes. The truth is-
はい　実は…
The truth is, like the lieutenant, I also fired one round at Research Laboratory 5 while escorting the Elric Brothers.
実は　第五研究所でエルリック兄弟護衛のために
私も　少尉とともに１発撃っているのです
What?
何？
I reported that, but they didn't listen at all.
そのことを　上申したのですが
相手にされませんでした
So they're planning on passing her off as the murderer?
少尉を犯人に仕立て上げるつもりか…
Now that I look closely, you're really scratched up.
よく見たら　いっぱい傷ついてる
Not an easy journey, huh?
ハードな旅してるのね
Say, what are you going to do now?
ねえ　これからどうするの？
Hey...
ねえ
I wonder...
どうすっかな…
Mama, don't cry.
ママ　泣かないで
What do you want me to do?
どうしてほしい？
What?
なんだよ
No, it's just that you've never asked me for advice about something concerning yourselves...
あんたたち自身のことで
相談されたことなかったから…
Oh...
そっか
It really scares me.
怖かったよ
Both of you are fighting in a place so dangerous that Mr. Hughes was killed.
ヒューズさんが殺されちゃうような危ない場所で
エドもアルも　ずっと戦ってる
I got really scared when I thought about that.
そう思ったら　すごく怖くなった
Because... you both could die.
だって　死んじゃうかもしれない
And suddenly disappear from my side.
急に私の目の前からいなくなる…
Just like Mom and Dad...
父さんと母さんみたいに
I got really scared when I thought about that.
そう思ったら　すごく怖くなった
To be honest, I want you to end your journey.
正直　旅をやめてほしいって思った
I want you two to get your bodies back.
元の体には戻ってほしい
But I don't want you to go on any dangerous journeys.
けど　危ない旅はやめてほしい
Because...
だって…
But...
でも…
Sorry.
ごめん
I don't really know what I want either.
私も　どうしたいか分かんないや
You're really kind, Winry.
ウィンリィは　優しいね
Huh?! W-W-What are you saying?
な…　何言ってんのよ！
I'm always kind!
私は　いつだって優しいのよ！
Stop! You're going to scratch me up even more!
やめて！傷が増えるってば…
PLACEHOLDER
Geez Al, what are you saying?
There.
ほいよ
Evening paper!
夕刊です
おっ　来た　来た！
Finally!
What, the paper again?
なんだよ　また新聞か
I'm forced to watch over you all day.
一日中　貴様とつきあわされてんだ
This is about the only thing I can look forward to.
このくらいしか楽しみは…
Warrant Officer Falman speaking. I'm calling from an outside line.
ファルマン准尉です　外から掛けてます
Please put me through to Colonel Mustang.
マスタング大佐につないでください
That's right. My code is...
そうです　コードは…
What's the deal?
なんだよ　騒がしいな
Airam, George, Oliver, 4649.
アイラム　ジョージ　オリバー　４６４９
ん？　こいつはあんときのねえちゃん
It's that lady from back then!
Philosopher's stones...
賢者の石
Ones who have tattoos of Ouroboros...
ウロボロスの印を持つ者たち
Homunculus...
人造人間
How are they...
どうやって…
Brother!
兄さん！
Look at this...
これ…
Don't scare me like that.
びっくりさせんなよ
I... got this from the front desk!
フロントで…　新聞！
What is it?
なんだよ
What?!
なんだと
"Second Lieutenant Maria Ross convicted on charges of the murder of Brigadier General Hughes"?!
マリア·ロス少尉を
ヒューズ准将殺害事件の犯人と断定
I don't believe this.
信じられない
Maybe the colonel or the major might know something.
大佐か少佐なら　何か知ってるかもしれない
Aren't you going to tell Winry?
ウィンリィには？
I'll explain it to her later.
あとで説明する
I don't like this thing.
やだなぁ　これ
Quit complaining. It's kind of like a collar for a dog.
文句言うな　犬っころの首輪みたいなもんだ
Oh, and I'm going to ask again just to be sure...
ところで　もう一回聞くが
Are you really fifteen?
お前　ほんとに１５歳か？
Yeah.
そうだよ
Stop lying.
うそつけ
But it's true...
ほんとだよ
What's all this?
なんだ？
What's going on?
どうした？
An intruder!
侵入者です！手を貸してください！
Please lend us a hand!
What?!
何っ
You'd better behave!
おとなしくしてろよ！
Yes, sir!
はい！
Weak, weak, weak!
ぬるい　ぬるい　ぬるい！
Are you guys even trying?!
やる気あんのか　おめぇら！
What's with this guy?!
なんだ　こいつは
Guns aren't working at all!
銃が効かないぞ！
Move!
どけっ！　この…
You-
Whoa!
But it's awfully boring not being allowed to cut them.
しかし　斬っちゃいけねぇってのは　つまんねぇな
Hello! Guy who's not affected by guns!
もしもし　銃が効かない人
Could you let me out of here?
こっから出して！
Who are you?
なんだ　おめぇ？
An illegal alien from Xing.
シンからの密入国者です
Oh, I see.
ああ　そう　遠い国から　ご苦労さん
Must have been a long trip.
I'll help you if you let me out!
出してくれたら手伝うよ
I don't have time to mess around with you...
おめぇに構ってる暇は…
What country did you say you're from?
どこの国だって？
Xing of the East.
東のシンだよ
Come with me.
一緒に来な
Thanks.
ありがとね
What?
何？
Hello, Honey!
ハロー　ハニー！
I've finally found you!
やっと見つけたぜ
You were at Research Laboratory 5-
第五研究所にいた…
I'm glad you remember me.
覚えててくれてうれしいねぇ
I think of you every time I see the hole in my right hand you shot through.
オレなんか
撃たれた右手の穴を見るたびに思い出してんだぜぇ
Ms. Murderer of Hughes.
ヒューズ殺しのねえちゃんよ
That's a misunderstanding!
それは誤解よ！
Is it really?
そうかぁ？
The paper says it's confirmed.
新聞は　犯人断定って書いてるぜ
No way...
そんな…
At this rate, it looks like you're going to have the guilt pinned on you and get executed by a firing squad.
おめぇさん　このままだと　罪を着せられて銃殺刑だぜ
You're kidding...
うそ…　うそよ
There's no way... If they investigate thoroughly-
ちゃんと調査すれば…
Make a decision!
選びな！
Get tortured to death by these guys or escape with me!
このままなぶり殺しにされるか
オレと一緒に逃げるか
Those are the two choices you've got!
二つに一つだ！
That's horrible...
最悪だわ…
Are those the only choices available?
それ以外に選択肢はないの？
Looks that way.
ないみたいだよ
God, damn it!
ああ　もう！　お父さん　お母さん　ごめんなさい
Mom, Dad, I'm sorry!
Fine, I'll escape. Happy?
逃げるわよ　逃げりゃいいんでしょ
You'd better escort me, you stupid bone armor!
ちゃんとエスコートしなさいよ　このバカ骨鎧！
Wow, you've got spunk.
おお　威勢がいいねぇ！
Women have to have guts!
女は度胸！
Yes.
はい　はい
Yes, I understand.
了解しました
Notify the entire city.
市内全域に通達　マリア·ロスが脱獄
Maria Ross has escaped from jail.
She's with a fiendish partner. Capture her immediately.
凶悪な同伴者がいるもよう　直ちに捕えよ
If she resists...
抵抗すれば
...don't hesitate to kill her!
射殺してかまわない！
How much longer are we going to run?!
どこまで逃げるの
Shut up and keep running!
いいから　走れ！
Second Lieutenant Ross?!
ロス少尉
Edward! Alphonse!
エドワード君！アルフォンス君！
Hey! You're that guy from-
ああ　あのときの！
And Ling, too?!
って　リンまで！
Hiya!
いや　君たち何してるの？
What are you guys up to?
That's what we should be asking!
そりゃ　こっちのセリフだ！
ええい　時間ねぇんだよ！
We don't have much time!
You...
この…
Lady, go straight down that alley to reach the warehouse district!
ねえちゃん
そこの裏道から　一直線に倉庫街に逃げな！
It's dark enough over there to make your escape!
あそこの暗闇なら　逃げきれる！
Second Lieutenant Ross, about Lt. Colonel Hughes...
ロス少尉！ヒューズ中佐を…
Hurry up! If the military police finds you, they'll shoot you dead!
急げ！憲兵が来たら　射殺されるぞ！
Second Lieutenant Ross!
ロス少尉！
Don't follow her!
来るんじゃねぇ！
Second Lieutenant!
少尉！
Second Lieutenant Ross!
ロス少尉！
You're Maria Ross, right?
マリア·ロスだな？
What?!
何っ？
Oh, so she did it?
おお　やったか
Hey!
って　おい！待て　こら！
Hold it!
Whoa!
おっと　危ねぇ！
We're going, thin-eyes!
行くぞ　糸目の！
ほいほい
You got it!
ちょっ…　リン！
Ling! Why are you working with a guy like that?!
なんで　そんなヤツと一緒にいるんだ！
We'll talk later!
あとで話すよ
Seriously...
もう！
やあ　鋼の
Yo, Fullmetal.
What's the meaning of this...
どういうことだ…
What's the meaning of this, Colonel?!
どういうことだ　大佐！
Why...
なんでだ…
Lt. Colonel Hughes was...
ヒューズ中佐は…
どうして　ロス少尉が…
Why would Second Lieutenant Ross...
なんで黙ってた
Why didn't you tell me in the first place?!
Attacking a superior?
上官に手を上げるか
身の程をわきまえろ！
Know your place!
You can't, Brother!
ダメだ　兄さん！
Let go of me, Al!
放せ　アル！
No!
ダメだって！
This bastard just killed Second Lieutenant Ross!
この野郎は　ロス少尉を！
Second Lieutenant Ross?
ロス少尉？
どういうことですか　大佐！
What is this, Colonel?!
脱獄したマリア·ロスには射殺命令が出ていた
There was a kill-on-sight order issued for Maria Ross, an escaped convict.
それだけだ
That's all there is to it.
"That's all"?!
それだけって！
I do apologize for hiding Hughes' death.
ヒューズの死を　隠したことは謝ろう
But do not object to orders. Do not seek explanation.
だが　命令に異を唱えるな　説明を求めるな
Simply obey.
ただ従え
That's what it means to be a soldier!
それが軍というものだ！
Colonel Mustang.
マスタング大佐
Explain the situation to me.
どういうことか　説明してくれ
抵抗すれば　射殺してよしとの通達が出ていたはずだ
There should have been a notice issued saying if she resists, we could gun her down.
抵抗されたから　殺したまでだ
She resisted, so I killed her.
准将は君の親友だったそうだな
The Brigadier General was a good friend of yours from what I hear.
Yeah.
いいヤツだった
He was a good man.
ロス少尉を脱獄させたのは
It weren't your men who helped
Second Lieutenant Ross escape from jail, right?
君の手の者じゃないだろうな？
Mine?
私が？なぜ
Why would I?
Why?
なぜ？
ああやって　自分の手で焼き殺すためさ
So you could burn her to death like that yourself.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't make assumptions.
憶測で物を言わないでもらいたい
I'm truly sorry for not telling you about Brigadier General Hughes' death.
ヒューズ准将の死を伝えなかったのは
本当にすまなかった
Because of me...
オレのせいで…
Don't brood over it.
思い詰めてはいかん
It is not your fault.
お主のせいではない
おそろいか
So you're all here.
ノックス先生
Dr. Nox...
The damage is extensive.
なんせ　損傷がひどくてな
But from a scar on her tooth that was just narrowly left unscathed, we were able to identify her as Maria Ross.
だが　かろうじて残された歯の治療痕から
マリア·ロスと断定した
ひでぇもんだ
How horrible.
Turning a babe like that into charcoal.
こんな　べっぴんさんを炭にしちまいやがって
よほど　恨みがあるんだろうな　マスタングさんよ
You must have really had something against her, eh, Mr. Mustang?
Are you satisfied you were able to avenge your friend's death?
敵討ちができて　満足かい？
It makes me sick a hero from the Ishbal War
would go so far against a little girl.
イシュヴァール戦の英雄が小娘相手にここまでやるたぁ
ヘドが出るね
大佐　この度は　我が輩の部下がとんだことを
Colonel, I can't express to you how sorry I am for what my subordinate did.
ロス少尉が　殺人を犯すとは…
I had no idea Second Lieutenant Ross would murder...
She's always been honest... hardworking...
彼女は　正直者で　まじめで…
思いやりのある…
And thoughtful...
Looks like you're exhausted, Major.
疲れがたまっているようだな　少佐
Why not take a vacation?
休暇を取るといい
Eastern Headquarters, where I used to be stationed, was great.
私がいた東部　あそこはいいぞ
It lacks the bustle of large cities,
and most of all, there are so many beauties.
都会のけん騒もないし　何より　美人が多い
And so, Mustang was able to avenge his best friend.
というわけで
マスタング君は見事親友の敵を討ちましたとさ
めでたし　めでたし
And everyone lived happily ever after.
You petered out.
詰めが甘いんじゃない？
大佐におとなしくしてもらうための
Wasn't the purpose of this mission to make the colonel behave?
作戦だったんでしょ？
Who cares?
いいじゃん
The dog ate its bait.
狗が餌を食べちゃったってのもオツでさ
And it seems he's provoking people's antipathy.
それに　反感買ってるみたいだぜ
部下にも　愛想尽かされるんじゃない？
His own men may even be disgusted at him.
What's this?
何かね？
休暇願いです
Request for leave.
At this time of the year?
この時期にかね
Is something wrong?
いけませんか？
No, it's fine. I permit it.
いや　いいだろう
許可する
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
Oh, for crying out loud!
貴様というヤツは
勝手に出歩いて
Why did you leave this place?! There's no knowing what the colonel will say to me if he finds out!
バレたら大佐になんて言われるか！
No one saw me coming back.
帰って来るときは　誰にも見られてねぇよ
That's not the problem here!
そういう問題じゃなくて！
You're a poor soldier that's in the hands of a vicious criminal, so it's okay.
おめぇは　凶悪な犯人に捕まってる
かわいそうな軍人さんなんだから　いいんだよ
Huh?!
はあ？
よう！さっきから何やってんだ？
Yo, what are you doing?
Sending a signal.
狼煙だよ
Signal?
狼煙？
And besides, why did you bring back some random stranger?!
だいたい
見ず知らずの人間を連れてくるなんて　何考えてんだ
若！捜しましたぞ
Young Master! We've looked all over for you!
Oh wow, that was quick.
おお　早かったな
More guests.
また増えたぞ
Hey Elizabeth! How are you?
やあ　エリザベス！元気かい？
Thanks for calling all the time.
いつもお電話　ありがとう
But won't your scary aide scold you if you slack off too much?
あんまりサボると　怖い副官に怒られるんじゃないの？
It's all right! She's on leave right now.
大丈夫だよ　彼女は休みだから！
Which is why I can call you like this.
お陰で　こうやって　君のところに電話を掛けられる
What do you think?
どうよ？　あれ
This starts as soon as the lieutenant goes on vacation.
中尉が　休みになった途端　これだ
I guess she really was...
ほんとにあの人…
...His babysitter...
お守りだったんだな
That's right!
そうなんだよ！
私もこっちに来てから　休みなしだったからね
I haven't had any days off since I came here.
So I'm thinking about taking a holiday soon.
そろそろ休暇を取ろうと思ってる
Oh? Going somewhere?
あら　どこかへ　お出かけ？
I've gotten into fishing lately.
最近　釣りにはまっててね
一緒にどうだ？
Want to come along?
Yes?
はい　どちら様…
Who is it-
Why did you do that all of a sudden, Major?!
いきなり　何すんだよ　少佐！
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric.
Oh no.
いかん　機械鎧が壊れてしまったな
Your automail is broken.
Huh?
Yes. This is a serious situation.
ゆゆしき事態である
We must get it fixed right away.
すぐに直さねばならん
我が輩が　リゼンブールまで送ってしんぜよう
I'll escort you to Resembool.
Well, umm...
いや　あの…
What? What?
何？何？
We're going back to Resembool?
リゼンブールに帰るの？
Al, listen to this...
おう　アル　聞いてくれよ…
Alphonse Elric, you stick out too much, so stay in Central.
アルフォンス·エルリック
お主は目立つから　セントラルにいるように
All right! Let's make arrangements for the train ride.
よし！　すぐに汽車の手配だ
行くぞ　エドワード·エルリック！
Let's go, Edward Elric!
Can you cut it out already, Major?
いいかげんにしてくれよ　少佐
No can do.
そうはいかんのだ
これも命令だからな
This is also an order.
あの男の…
From that man...
はい　了解しました
Yes, I understand.
Major Armstrong and Edward Elric just got on a train.
アームストロング少佐とエドワード·エルリックが
汽車に乗ったそうです
I see.
そうか
Now there are no hindrances.
これで　邪魔者はいなくなった
I was able to come in contact with a witness who saw the guy who assaulted the prison.
留置所襲撃犯の目撃者に　接触できたよ
And this is what he looks like.
で　これが犯人の似顔絵
Oh, he was alive?
あら　生きてたのね
I wonder if he has anything to do with the Flame Colonel?
焔の大佐とつながりが？
Who knows?
さあねぇ？だけど可能性は大じゃないかな
But I think we can say for sure that there is a big possibility.
Where did he run off to?
どこに逃げたの？
Well, he's speedy, and to top it off,
he's also good at hiding...
いや　逃げ足は速いわ　隠れるのが上手だわ…
So in other words, you don't know?
要するに分かんないんでしょ？無能ね
You're so incompetent.
Shut up, hag.
うるさいな　おばはんは
We don't have enough people, that's why.
人手が足りないんだよ
People?
人手？
He's all we need.
人手はこれで十分よ
You're up, Barry the Chopper.
さあ　出番よ
バリー·ザ·チョッパー
Let it all out, Let it all out
I don't have to act tough, right?
強がらなくていいんだね
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
誰かが描いてった
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
壁の落書きの花が　揺れる
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
自分らしさなんて, 誰もわからないよ
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
長い長い道の途中で
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
失くしたり, 拾ったり,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
急に寂しくなって, 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
涙も　痛みも　星に変えよう
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
明日を照らす　灯りをともそう
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
小さな手かざして　ふたりで作ろう
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
星屑を　強く光る永遠を探そう
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
さよなら　いつかは来るかもしれない
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
季節はそれでも巡り巡ってく
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
小さく迷っても　歩いてく
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
君と歩いてく
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
日本語字幕仕上げ：虚無の才犬
すべての真実は　クセルクセスにあり
The whole truth lies in Xerxes.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
朽ち果て消えた街に残された人が
The residents left in the city that rusted away and disappeared...
少年の闇を払拭する
...wipe away the darkness within the boy.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal Alchemist
第十八話　小さな人間の傲慢な掌
Episode 18, The Arrogant Palm of a Small Human.
人間よ　反撃の狼煙を上げろ
Humans, raise the signal of counterattack.